[
    {
        "question": "さ来年",
        "answer": "さらいねん"
    },
    {
        "question": "大きい",
        "answer": "おおきい"
    },
    {
        "question": "英語",
        "answer": "えいご"
    },
    {
        "question": "大好き",
        "answer": "だいすき"
    },
    {
        "question": "話す",
        "answer": "はなす"
    },
    {
        "question": "小さな",
        "answer": "ちいさな"
    },
    {
        "question": "四日",
        "answer": "よっか"
    },
    {
        "question": "時々",
        "answer": "ときどき"
    },
    {
        "question": "有名",
        "answer": "ゆうめい"
    },
    {
        "question": "上",
        "answer": "うえ"
    },
    {
        "question": "出口",
        "answer": "でぐち"
    },
    {
        "question": "百",
        "answer": "ひゃく"
    },
    {
        "question": "本棚",
        "answer": "ほんだな"
    },
    {
        "question": "十",
        "answer": "じゅう  とお"
    },
    {
        "question": "水曜日",
        "answer": "すいようび"
    },
    {
        "question": "学校",
        "answer": "がっこう"
    },
    {
        "question": "お金",
        "answer": "おかね"
    },
    {
        "question": "電話",
        "answer": "でんわ"
    },
    {
        "question": "毎年",
        "answer": [
            "まいねん",
            "まいとし"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "二つ",
        "answer": "ふたつ"
    },
    {
        "question": "読む",
        "answer": "よむ"
    },
    {
        "question": "土曜日",
        "answer": "どようび"
    },
    {
        "question": "生まれる",
        "answer": "うまれる"
    },
    {
        "question": "午前",
        "answer": "ごぜん"
    },
    {
        "question": "八つ",
        "answer": "やっつ"
    },
    {
        "question": "休む",
        "answer": "やすむ"
    },
    {
        "question": "二十日",
        "answer": "はつか"
    },
    {
        "question": "三",
        "answer": "さん"
    },
    {
        "question": "南",
        "answer": "みなみ"
    },
    {
        "question": "二日",
        "answer": "ふつか"
    },
    {
        "question": "二人",
        "answer": "ふたり"
    },
    {
        "question": "午後",
        "answer": "ごご"
    },
    {
        "question": "今日",
        "answer": "きょう"
    },
    {
        "question": "一日",
        "answer": "いちにち"
    },
    {
        "question": "入れる",
        "answer": "いれる"
    },
    {
        "question": "今週",
        "answer": "こんしゅう"
    },
    {
        "question": "地下鉄",
        "answer": "ちかてつ"
    },
    {
        "question": "留学生",
        "answer": "りゅうがくせい"
    },
    {
        "question": "今月",
        "answer": "こんげつ"
    },
    {
        "question": "左",
        "answer": "ひだり"
    },
    {
        "question": "聞く",
        "answer": "きく"
    },
    {
        "question": "休み",
        "answer": "やすみ"
    },
    {
        "question": "新聞",
        "answer": "しんぶん"
    },
    {
        "question": "何",
        "answer": [
            "なん",
            "なに"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "お父さん",
        "answer": "おとうさん"
    },
    {
        "question": "元気",
        "answer": "げんき"
    },
    {
        "question": "名前",
        "answer": "なまえ"
    },
    {
        "question": "一",
        "answer": "いち"
    },
    {
        "question": "廊下",
        "answer": "ろうか"
    },
    {
        "question": "一緒",
        "answer": "いっしょ"
    },
    {
        "question": "電気",
        "answer": "でんき"
    },
    {
        "question": "夏休み",
        "answer": "なつやすみ"
    },
    {
        "question": "毎晩",
        "answer": "まいばん"
    },
    {
        "question": "外",
        "answer": "そと"
    },
    {
        "question": "伯母さん/叔母さん",
        "answer": "おばさん"
    },
    {
        "question": "年",
        "answer": "とし"
    },
    {
        "question": "火曜日",
        "answer": "かようび"
    },
    {
        "question": "時計",
        "answer": "とけい"
    },
    {
        "question": "大丈夫",
        "answer": "だいじょうぶ"
    },
    {
        "question": "来週",
        "answer": "らいしゅう"
    },
    {
        "question": "下手",
        "answer": "へた"
    },
    {
        "question": "病気",
        "answer": "びょうき"
    },
    {
        "question": "来る",
        "answer": "くる"
    },
    {
        "question": "毎日",
        "answer": "まいにち"
    },
    {
        "question": "中",
        "answer": "なか"
    },
    {
        "question": "今",
        "answer": "いま"
    },
    {
        "question": "食堂",
        "answer": "しょくどう"
    },
    {
        "question": "万年筆",
        "answer": "まんねんひつ"
    },
    {
        "question": "本",
        "answer": "ほん"
    },
    {
        "question": "大人",
        "answer": "おとな"
    },
    {
        "question": "東",
        "answer": "ひがし"
    },
    {
        "question": "一昨年",
        "answer": "おととし"
    },
    {
        "question": "電車",
        "answer": "でんしゃ"
    },
    {
        "question": "飛行機",
        "answer": "ひこうき"
    },
    {
        "question": "前",
        "answer": "まえ"
    },
    {
        "question": "去年",
        "answer": "きょねん"
    },
    {
        "question": "下",
        "answer": "した"
    },
    {
        "question": "先週",
        "answer": "せんしゅう"
    },
    {
        "question": "大切",
        "answer": "たいせつ"
    },
    {
        "question": "二",
        "answer": "に"
    },
    {
        "question": "九",
        "answer": [
            "きゅう",
            "く"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "丸い/円い",
        "answer": "まるい"
    },
    {
        "question": "友達",
        "answer": "ともだち"
    },
    {
        "question": "誕生日",
        "answer": "たんじょうび"
    },
    {
        "question": "毎朝",
        "answer": "まいあさ"
    },
    {
        "question": "日曜日",
        "answer": "にちようび"
    },
    {
        "question": "半分",
        "answer": "はんぶん"
    },
    {
        "question": "外国",
        "answer": "がいこく"
    },
    {
        "question": "葉書",
        "answer": "はがき"
    },
    {
        "question": "六",
        "answer": "ろく"
    },
    {
        "question": "木曜日",
        "answer": "もくようび"
    },
    {
        "question": "図書館",
        "answer": "としょかん"
    },
    {
        "question": "今朝",
        "answer": "けさ"
    },
    {
        "question": "毎週",
        "answer": "まいしゅう"
    },
    {
        "question": "木",
        "answer": "き"
    },
    {
        "question": "三日",
        "answer": "みっか"
    },
    {
        "question": "書く",
        "answer": "かく"
    },
    {
        "question": "上げる",
        "answer": "あげる"
    },
    {
        "question": "先",
        "answer": "さき"
    },
    {
        "question": "白",
        "answer": "しろ"
    },
    {
        "question": "月曜日",
        "answer": "げつようび"
    },
    {
        "question": "出かける",
        "answer": "でかける"
    },
    {
        "question": "七つ",
        "answer": "ななつ"
    },
    {
        "question": "五つ",
        "answer": "いつつ"
    },
    {
        "question": "九日",
        "answer": "ここのか"
    },
    {
        "question": "大勢",
        "answer": "おおぜい"
    },
    {
        "question": "上着",
        "answer": "うわぎ"
    },
    {
        "question": "自動車",
        "answer": "じどうしゃ"
    },
    {
        "question": "三つ",
        "answer": "みっつ"
    },
    {
        "question": "女の子",
        "answer": "おんなのこ"
    },
    {
        "question": "出る",
        "answer": "でる"
    },
    {
        "question": "国",
        "answer": "くに"
    },
    {
        "question": "靴下",
        "answer": "くつした"
    },
    {
        "question": "雨",
        "answer": "あめ"
    },
    {
        "question": "明日",
        "answer": "あした"
    },
    {
        "question": "もう一度",
        "answer": "もういちど"
    },
    {
        "question": "辞書",
        "answer": "じしょ"
    },
    {
        "question": "入口",
        "answer": "いりぐち"
    },
    {
        "question": "七",
        "answer": [
            "しち",
            "なな"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "後ろ",
        "answer": "うしろ"
    },
    {
        "question": "六つ",
        "answer": "むっつ"
    },
    {
        "question": "万",
        "answer": "まん"
    },
    {
        "question": "山",
        "answer": "やま"
    },
    {
        "question": "水",
        "answer": "みず"
    },
    {
        "question": "八",
        "answer": "はち"
    },
    {
        "question": "右",
        "answer": "みぎ"
    },
    {
        "question": "白い",
        "answer": "しろい"
    },
    {
        "question": "六日",
        "answer": "むいか"
    },
    {
        "question": "後",
        "answer": "あと"
    },
    {
        "question": "八日",
        "answer": "ようか"
    },
    {
        "question": "お菓子",
        "answer": "おかし"
    },
    {
        "question": "見せる",
        "answer": "みせる"
    },
    {
        "question": "今晩",
        "answer": "こんばん"
    },
    {
        "question": "七日",
        "answer": "なのか"
    },
    {
        "question": "高い",
        "answer": "たかい"
    },
    {
        "question": "川/河",
        "answer": "かわ"
    },
    {
        "question": "生徒",
        "answer": "せいと"
    },
    {
        "question": "金曜日",
        "answer": "きんようび"
    },
    {
        "question": "五",
        "answer": "ご"
    },
    {
        "question": "一昨日",
        "answer": "おととい"
    },
    {
        "question": "西",
        "answer": "にし"
    },
    {
        "question": "入る",
        "answer": "はいる"
    },
    {
        "question": "出す",
        "answer": "だす"
    },
    {
        "question": "二十歳",
        "answer": "はたち"
    },
    {
        "question": "小さい",
        "answer": "ちいさい"
    },
    {
        "question": "一つ",
        "answer": "ひとつ"
    },
    {
        "question": "食べる",
        "answer": "たべる"
    },
    {
        "question": "長い",
        "answer": "ながい"
    },
    {
        "question": "八百屋",
        "answer": "やおや"
    },
    {
        "question": "お母さん",
        "answer": "おかあさん"
    },
    {
        "question": "食べ物",
        "answer": "たべもの"
    },
    {
        "question": "昨日",
        "answer": "きのう"
    },
    {
        "question": "帽子",
        "answer": "ぼうし"
    },
    {
        "question": "毎月",
        "answer": [
            "まいげつ",
            "まいつき"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "話",
        "answer": "はなし"
    },
    {
        "question": "千",
        "answer": "せん"
    },
    {
        "question": "時間",
        "answer": "じかん"
    },
    {
        "question": "大使館",
        "answer": "たいしかん"
    },
    {
        "question": "今年",
        "answer": "ことし"
    },
    {
        "question": "四つ",
        "answer": "よっつ"
    },
    {
        "question": "先生",
        "answer": "せんせい"
    },
    {
        "question": "学生",
        "answer": "がくせい"
    },
    {
        "question": "外国人",
        "answer": "がいこくじん"
    },
    {
        "question": "女",
        "answer": "おんな"
    },
    {
        "question": "五日",
        "answer": "いつか"
    },
    {
        "question": "旅行",
        "answer": "りょこう"
    },
    {
        "question": "来月",
        "answer": "らいげつ"
    },
    {
        "question": "十日",
        "answer": "とおか"
    },
    {
        "question": "見る  観る",
        "answer": "みる"
    },
    {
        "question": "一月",
        "answer": ["ひとつき", "いちがつ"]
    },
    {
        "question": "半",
        "answer": "はん"
    },
    {
        "question": "男",
        "answer": "おとこ"
    },
    {
        "question": "行く",
        "answer": "いく"
    },
    {
        "question": "人",
        "answer": "ひと"
    },
    {
        "question": "車",
        "answer": "くるま"
    },
    {
        "question": "銀行",
        "answer": "ぎんこう"
    },
    {
        "question": "先月",
        "answer": "せんげつ"
    },
    {
        "question": "来年",
        "answer": "らいねん"
    },
    {
        "question": "子供",
        "answer": "こども"
    },
    {
        "question": "自転車",
        "answer": "じてんしゃ"
    },
    {
        "question": "伯父/叔父",
        "answer": "おじいさん"
    },
    {
        "question": "北",
        "answer": "きた"
    },
    {
        "question": "大きな",
        "answer": "おおきな"
    },
    {
        "question": "一人",
        "answer": "ひとり"
    },
    {
        "question": "四",
        "answer": [
            "し",
            "よん"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "九つ",
        "answer": "ここのつ"
    },
    {
        "question": "大学",
        "answer": "だいがく"
    },
    {
        "question": "上手",
        "answer": "じょうず"
    },
    {
        "question": "男の子",
        "answer": "おとこのこ"
    },
    {
        "question": "天気",
        "answer": "てんき"
    }
]